Do you realize we're getting married in four weeks?
你知道再四個星期 我們就要結婚了嗎？
Four weeks, baby. Four weeks!
四個星期，寶貝，四個星期！
You realize you get louder each week?
你知道每星期你都更大聲嗎？
There's still so much to do! Have you written your vows?
還有這麼多事要做！ 你寫好你的婚誓了嗎？
I figured I'd just buy those. "Pat, I'd like to buy a vow."
我想我會去買 「派得，我要買婚誓」
You know I've no sense of humor when it comes to this.
你知道講到婚禮的事 我是沒有幽默感的
-Right. Have you written yours yet? -No, but I know what I'm gonna say.
-是，你寫了你的嗎？ -不，我知道我要說什麼
Do you happen to know what I'm gonna say?
你會不會剛好知道 我要講什麼？
Let's do it now. It won't be hard.
現在來做，不會那麼難的
Say what's in your heart.
說你心裡想的
Look at her go. She must love me more than I love her!
看她寫得多快，她一定愛我 比我愛她多！
What's wrong with me? Oh, don't open that door.
我有什麼問題？ 不要打開那扇門
The One with the Vows
本集播出：婚誓
rainystar壓制iPod-MP4
"Monica, there are no words.."
「摩妮卡，沒有字…」
There are no words! This shouldn't be this hard!
沒有字！不應該這麼難的！
You've done this before. What did you say in your vows?
你做過這事 你的婚誓裡說什麼？
With Carol I promised never to love another woman until I die.
對卡蘿，我答應直到我死 不再愛另一個女人
She made no such promise.
她沒有這樣答應我
I'm pathetic. Monica knows what to say, you should have seen her.
我真悲哀，摩妮卡知道要講什麼 看她下筆如飛的樣子
What's the emergency?
什麼緊急大事？
You have to help me write my vows. All I have is this.
幫我忙，我需要寫我的婚誓 可是我只有這些
I like the pretty drawing of you in the wedding dress.
我喜歡你穿婚紗的圖劃
-Thank you. -Except your breasts look small.
除了你的胸部看來有點小
Those are my eyes!
那些是我的眼睛！
-Those are my breasts. -Oh, yeah.
-那是我的胸部 -是，好吧
Why don't you start with something simple?
何不從簡單的開始，像是：
"Monica, from the moment I met you I knew I loved you."
「摩妮卡，第一次見到你 我就知道我愛你」
I can't do that.
我不確定我能這麼說
Everyone, this is Chandler.
各位，這是錢德
Hi, I'm Ross' little sister.
我是羅斯的小妹
Okay.
是
Okay, okay. Maybe you could start with:
好，也許這樣起頭：
"Chandler, even though we were friends...
錢德，即使在我們還是朋友時…
there was a part of me that knew I wanted more."
一部份的我一直知道我要更多
All right, there's a nuclear holocaust. I'm the last man on Earth.
好吧，有一場核子浩劫 我是地球上最後一個男人
Would you go out with me?
你會和我約會嗎？
Are we allowed to lie in the vows?
婚誓裡可以說謊嗎？
Okay, don't talk about those feelings. Just say something about...
也許那時你不談你的感情
all the things he's taught you, like..
說些他教會你的事，像是…
Or all the things you taught him.
或是你教會他的事
Everybody knows the erogenous zones. One, two, three...
大家都知道基本的性感帶 有1，2，3…
four, five, six and seven.
4，5… 6和7
There are seven?
有7個？
-That's one? -Kind of an important one.
-那算是一個嗎？ -蠻重要的
I was looking at it upside down.
我是倒著看的
You know, sometimes that helps.
有時候這樣也有幫助的
Okay, start out with a little one...
好，現在，由1開始…
a two, a one-two-three...
一個2，一個123…
a three, a five...
一個3，一個5…
a four, a three-two...
一個4，一個32…
two, a two-four-six.
2，一個246
Two-four-six, four, two...
246，4，2…
two, four-seven...
2，47…
five-seven, six-seven...
57，67…
seven, seven...
7，7…
seven, seven, seven...
7，7，7，7，7…
seven!
7！
How about something like:
我知道了！這樣如何：
"Monica, when I look back over our time together..."
「摩妮卡，回顧我們在一起的時間…」
-Yeah? -I can't do all of it.
-然後？ -不能全部都要我做
Look back over your time together.
回顧你們在一起的時間
Oh, look, twins!
看，雙胞胎！
No fair! I don't even have one, how come they get two?
不公平！我連一個都沒有 為什麼他們有兩個？
-You'll get one. -Yeah, when?
-你會有一個的 -是啊，什麼時候？
When we're 40, if neither of us are married...
這樣吧 當我們40的時候，如果我們 都沒結婚，
-what do you say we have one? -Why wouldn't I be married?
-我們倆來生一個如何？ -我為什麼會40歲還沒結婚？
I just meant hypothetically.
不，不，我是說假設這樣
Hypothetically, why won't I be married?
假設這樣 我為什麼會40歲還沒結婚？
No, no.
不，不
What is it? Is there something unmarriable about me?
怎麼著？真的，我是有什麼 基本上不能結婚的地方嗎？
Well?
怎麼樣？
Dear God, this parachute is a knapsack!
我的老天 這個降落傘是一個背包！
I'm getting married today!
今天我要結婚了！
Think he knew I was here?
他知道我在這兒嗎？
Nice try.
算你盡力
Wait, wait, wait.
等一下，等一下，等一下
Look, Monica..
摩妮卡…
-This is not gonna work. -I bet this'll work.
-沒有用的 -我保證這有用
You are so great! I love you.
你真棒！我愛你
What?
什麼？
I said you're so great, and then I stopped talking.
沒事！我說，你真棒 然後就沒說話了
-You said you love me! -No, I didn't.
-你說你愛我！我不能相信 -不，我沒有
-Yes, you did. -No, I didn't!
-有，你有 -沒有，我沒有！
-You love me! -No, I don't!
-你愛我！ -不，我不！
Stop it! Stop it!
停！停！
You know, I was thinking, what if I unpack here?
我在想，如果我在這裡打開東西呢？
Then all your stuff would be here.
你的東西都會在這裡
Well...
那…
What if it was here?
如果我的東西都在這裡的話？
Then you'd be going back and forth all the time.
你會一直來來往往的
Doesn't make any sense.
沒什麼道理
Okay.
好
What if we live together, and you understand what I'm saying?
如果我們住在一起 你瞭解我在說什麼？
We wanted to surprise you.
你希望這是一個驚喜
Oh, my God!
我的天！
Chandler...
錢德…
in all my life...
我這一生…
I never thought I'd be so lucky...
從沒想過我會這麼幸運…
as to fall in love with my best..
能愛上我最好的…
My best.. There's a reason why girls don't do this!
我最好的… 女生不這麼做是有原因的！
Okay, okay, okay! I'll do it.
好，好，我來
I thought..
我想…
I can do this.
我做得到
I thought...
我以為…
that it mattered what I said or where I said it.
我說什麼和在哪裡說很重要
Then I realized the only thing that matters is that you..
但我發現唯一重要的是你…
You make me happier than I ever thought I could be.
你使我比我能想像的更快樂
And if you let me...
如果你願意…
I'll spend the rest of my life trying to make you feel the same way.
我要用這一生 來讓你有同樣感覺
Monica?
摩妮卡？
Will you marry me?
嫁給我好嗎？
Yes.
好
Can we come in? We're dying out here!
我們可以進來了嗎？ 我們要急死了！
Come in! Come in!
進來！進來！
-We're engaged! -Yes!
-我們訂婚了！ -好！
-Hi. -What have you guys been up to?
-嗨 -你們在幹嘛？
Helping Chandler write his vows. He kicked us out.
幫錢德寫他的婚誓 但被他踢出來了…
Joey kept making inappropriate suggestions.
因為喬伊一直做不恰當的建議
How is "Monica, I love your sweet ass" inappropriate?
「摩妮卡，我愛你的美臀」 有什麼不恰當？
How's Monica doing?
摩妮卡寫得怎麼樣？
Lucky she's got a sweet ass. She's not so good at writing.
這樣說吧，幸好她有一個美臀 因為她不太會寫
In four weeks they're gonna be married!
真不能相信再四個星期 他們就要結婚了！
Let's just hope it works.
希望他們的婚姻成功
Nine out of 10 marriages end in divorce.
10個裡面有9個以離婚收場
That's not true.
菲比，沒有的事
You're right. How's the missis?
是啊，你說的對，你太太們好嗎？
I can't believe...
真不能相信...
-they're together 3 years. -That long?
-...他們在一起3年了 -那麼久了？
It seems like less because they hid it from us.
感覺沒那麼久 因為他們瞞了我們很久
Hey, it's me. Coming in.
是我，進來了
I've had a very long, hard day.
我今天辛苦了一整天
-I'm getting some chicken. Want some? -No. Bye, then.
-我要去買炸雞，你要不要？ -不，謝了，不要炸雞，再見
He wouldn't leave. He kept asking if I wanted chicken.
你還好吧？抱歉，他不肯離開 一直問要不要炸雞
Chicken?
炸雞？
I could eat some chicken.
我可以來點炸雞
Hey, Joe!
喬伊！
Can I get a three-piece, coleslaw, beans and a Coke?
我想要三塊雞，沙拉 豆子，還有可樂
Diet Coke.
健怡可樂
-Why didn't they tell us? -I know, we were cool about it.
-我不知道他們為什麼不告訴我們 -好像我們不會認同似的
You? And you?
你？和你？
You cannot tell. No one knows.
你不能說，沒有人知道
How? When?
怎麼？何時？
-It happened in London. -In London?!
-在倫敦發生的 -在倫敦？！
We didn't want to make a big deal out of it.
我們沒告訴任何人 不希望把它變成大事
But it is a big deal!
可是這是大事！
-I have to tell someone. -No, no!
-我一定要告訴人 -不，不要！
-You can't. -Please!
-你不能 -拜託！
We don't want to deal with telling them. Just promise you won't tell.
我們不想面對告訴大家之後的事 答應我你不會說
All right!
好！
I can't wait to be with you. I'll tell Rachel I'm doing laundry.
等不及要和你在一起了，我告訴瑞秋我要洗幾個小時的衣服
Laundry? Is that my new nickname?
洗衣服？是我的新暱稱嗎？
You know your nickname, Mr. Big..
你知道你的暱稱是什麼，大…
Oh, look, there's Monica and Chandler. Hey! Hey, you guys! Hey!
看，是摩妮卡和錢德 嘿！嘿，你們兩個！嘿！
Chandler and Monica!
錢德和摩妮卡！ 錢德和摩妮卡！
Oh, my God!
我的天！
-Chandler and Monica! -Oh, my God!
-錢德和摩妮卡！ -我的天！
-Oh, my eyes! My eyes! -Phoebe! Phoebe!
-我的眼睛！我的眼睛！ -菲比！菲比！
-It's okay! It's okay! -No! They're doing it!
-沒事的！沒事的！ -不！他們在親熱！
I know! I know!
我知道！我知道！
-You know? -Yes!
-你知道？ -對，我知道！
And Joey, but Ross doesn't, so stop screaming!
喬伊知道，但羅斯不知道 你得停止尖叫！
-Hey, what's going on? -Oh, hi!
-怎麼樣啊？ -嗨！
What? What?
什麼？什麼？
We're excited that you might get this place!
老天！我們好興奮 你可能會搬來這兒！
-Actually, it looks really good. -It looks pretty good!
-事實上，看起來不錯 -看來很不錯！
Get in here! Come on!
過來這裡！來！
So they don't know that Rachel knows?
他們知道你知道 但他們不知道瑞秋知道？
Yes, but it doesn't matter who knows what.
對，但你知道嗎？ 誰知道什麼並不重要
Enough of us know. We can just tell them we know.
現在有足夠的人知道了 就可以告訴他們我們知道
The lying and the secrets will be over.
謊言，秘密終於可以結束了
Or, we can not tell them we know and have a little fun of our own.
或者我們不要告訴他們我們知道 我們可以找點小樂子
We better go if we're gonna catch that movie.
好，該走了，如果想趕上電影的話
-Bye. -Bye.
-再見 -再見
Bye, Chandler. I miss you already.
再見，錢德，我已經開始想你了
Did you see the inappropriate pinching?
你看到了嗎？ 她很不恰當地捏我一下？
Actually, I did.
我看到了
So now do you believe that she's attracted to me?
你現在相信她喜歡上我了吧？
Oh, my God! My God, she knows about us!
我的天！ 我的天，她知道我們的事！
-Phoebe knows about us! -I didn't tell them.
-菲比知道我們的事！ -我沒有告訴她們
Them? Who's them?
她們？誰是她們？
Phoebe and Joey.
菲比和喬伊
Joey!
喬伊！
And Rachel.
還有瑞秋
They made me promise not to tell.
我本來要告訴你們的 可是她們要我答應不說
They think they are so slick, messing with us!
她們以為他們很厲害，玩我們！
They don't know that we know that they know.
可是，他們不知道 我們知道他們知道
-So... -Ah, yes!
-所以… -對！
The messers become the messees!
玩人的變成被玩的！
My God, he wants me to come over and feel his biceps!
我的天，他要我過去 摸他的二頭肌還有別的！
Are you kidding?
你開玩笑？
I can't believe he'd do that to Mo..
我不相信他會對摩妮卡這樣…
Joey? Do they know that we know?
喬伊？他們知道我們知道了嗎？
-No. -Joey!
-不 -喬伊！
-They know you know. -I knew it!
-他們知道你們知道 -我就知道！
I cannot believe those two!
不能相信這兩個人！
They thought that they could mess with us? With us?
他們以為可以玩我們？ 他們想要玩我們？
They don't know that we know they know we know.
他們不知道我們知道 他們知道我們知道
Joey, you can't say anything.
喬伊，你什麼也不能說
Couldn't if I wanted to.
即使我想說也不知道要怎麼說
She wants me to put lotion on her!
這完全失控了！ 她要我替她抹乳液！
She's bluffing!
她說大話！
She's not backing down. She went like this.
她沒有退縮，她像這樣：
He's not backing down. He went to get lotion.
他沒有退縮，他去拿乳液了
Aren't you guys done yet?
你們還沒玩完嗎？
The sooner Phoebe breaks Chandler the sooner this is all over.
菲比早點攻破錢德 這事就早一點完全公開
-I like that. -Okay.
-我喜歡 -好
Okay, show him your bra. He's afraid of bras. Can't work them.
好，給他看你的內衣 他最怕內衣，他不會解內衣
Wow! You didn't rip off any buttons.
哇！你沒拉掉任何扣子
It's not my first time.
這不是第一次
You go seduce her until she cracks.
回去那兒 勾引她直到解決她
Okay, give me a second.
好，給我一秒鐘
-Did you clean up in here? -Of course.
-你清理了這兒？ -當然
Oh, you're going?
你要走了？
Not without you, lover.
除非你一起來，愛人
So, this is my bra.
這是我的內衣
It's very, very nice.
非常非常的好看
Well, come here.
過來
I'm happy we're gonna have all the sex.
我非常開心我們要上床了
You should be. I'm very bendy.
你應該開心的，我的柔軟度很好
-I'm gonna kiss you. -Not if I kiss you first.
-我現在要吻你了 -如果我沒先吻你的話
There's nothing left for us to do but kiss.
我想我們除了接吻 沒有別的事可做了
Here it comes.
來了
Our first kiss.
我們的初吻
-Okay, okay, okay, fine, you win! -Ha!
-好，好，好，好，你贏了！ -哈！
-I can't have sex. -Why not?
-我不能和你上床 -為什麼不？
-I'm in love with Monica. -You're what?
-因為我愛摩妮卡 -你什麼？
Love her! That's right, I love her! I love her!
愛她！對，我愛她！ 我愛她！
I love you, Monica.
我愛你，摩妮卡
I love you too, Chandler.
我也愛你，錢德
I thought you guys were doing it, I didn't know you were in love.
我以為你們兩個只是上床 我不知道你們戀愛了
That's it, it's over. Everybody knows.
就是這樣，結束了 大家都知道了
-Well, Ross doesn't. -We'd like it if no one told him yet.
-其實，羅斯還不知道 -請大家先不要告訴他
No.
不
What are you doing?
你在幹什麼？
Get off my sister!
放開我妹妹！
Friends getting married, it's gotta change things.
朋友要結婚了 很多事會改變的
Think it'll be different?
你想會不一樣嗎？
How can it not be? They're gonna have kids...
怎麼能不變呢？ 他們很快會有小孩…
and hang out with other couples who have kids.
會和其他有孩子的夫婦在一起
And maybe they'll leave the city...
也許他們會搬離城市…
to be near a Volvo dealership.
到某個靠近富豪車商的地方
Things change.
事情會變的
I don't want them to move to a Volvo dealership.
我不要他們搬到 賣富豪車的地方
It'll be okay, Joe.
喬伊，會沒事的
Sorry. I just.. I like things the way they are.
抱歉，我只是… 我希望能像以前一樣
Who's this little naked guy?
這個光著身子的小孩是誰？
That naked guy would be me.
這個光著身子的小孩是我
Look at the little thing.
你看看這小東西
Yes.
是啊
Yes, fine, that is my penis. Can we be grownups now?
是，好，那是我的小雞雞 我們現在可以做大人了嗎？
-Who are those people? -Got me.
-這些是誰？ -問倒我了
Oh, that's Nana right there.
那中間的是奶奶
-Wow. -Let's see.
-哇 -我看看
"Me and the gang at Java Joe's."
「我和在爪哇喬店裡的那一群」
Monica, you look like your grandma. How old was she?
摩妮卡，你很像你祖母 那時她幾歲？
Let's see,1939.
我看看，1939
Yeah,24,25.
對，24，25
Looks like a fun gang.
看來很快樂的一群
Look, look, look! I got Monica naked.
看，看，看！ 我找到摩妮卡光著身子的
Let me see.
我看
No, that would be me again.
不，這還是我
-Hey, you guys. -What's going on?
-嘿，大夥兒 -怎麼樣啊？
Well, we were just talking about...
我們剛剛提到…
you guys getting married and how great it is.
你們要結婚了，非常的好
Yeah, you can get a Volvo. If that's what you really want.
對，你們會買一台富豪 如果你們真的要那樣
That's so sweet.
你們真好
-So, we both finished our vows. -Can we read them?
-我們都寫完了婚誓 -可以看嗎？
As long as I don't hear his and he doesn't hear mine.
只要我不看到錢德的 他不看到我的就好
Oh, that's beautiful.
好美
Funny one! Good!
好好笑！很好！
Will you marry me?
摩妮卡，你嫁給我好嗎？
What? I don't get it.
什麼？我不懂
Oh, yeah!
是呦！
-Man, this is hilarious! -Chandler!
-這太爆笑了！ -錢德！
Don't worry, we'll make yours funnier.
甜心，別擔心 我們會讓你的好笑一點
Okay, what do you think?
你們覺得如何？
-Dude... -I have never known love like this.
-老兄… -我從沒見過這樣的愛
-You really like it? -Dude!
-你真的喜歡？ -老兄！
How did you write this?
你怎麼寫出來的？
I stole Monica's and changed the name.
我偷了摩妮卡的 改成我的名字
-You can't do that! -If he goes first he can!
-你不能這麼做！ -如果他先講的話就可以！